He rides again.
Ghost Rider: Spirit of Vengeance is a action, fantasy,
thriller film directed by Mark Neveldine.
When the devil resurfaces with aims to take over the world in human form, Johnny Blaze reluctantly comes out of hiding to
transform into the flame-spewing supernatural hero Ghost Rider -- and rescue a 10-year-old boy from an unsavory end.
Johnny Blaze / Ghost Rider, played by Nicolas Cage.
Danny, played by Fergus Riordan.
Nadya, played by Violante Placido.
Roarke, played by Ciarán Hinds.
Ray Carrigan, played by Johnny Whitworth.
Moreau, played by Idris Elba.
Ghost Rider: Spirit of Vengeance is a 2011 American superhero film
based on the Marvel Comics antihero Ghost Rider.
It is a sequel to the 2007 film Ghost Rider and features Nicolas Cage reprising his role as Johnny Blaze / Ghost Rider with
supporting roles portrayed by Ciarán Hinds, Violante Placido, Johnny Whitworth, Christopher Lambert, and Idris Elba.
The film was directed by Mark Neveldine and Brian
Taylor, from a screenplay written by Scott M.
Gimple, Seth Hoffman, and David S.
Released publicly for one night on December 11, 2011, Ghost Rider: Spirit of Vengeance
had its wide commercial release on February 17, 2012, in 2D and 3D.
Johnny Blaze is the Ghost Rider cursed to hunt demons, and he is approached by a secret religious sect to
help protect a young boy named Danny, who is believed to be a target of the devil's minions.
The film experienced worse critical reception than the first film, with
criticism being aimed towards the script, CGI, and performances.
The film grossed $132.6 – 149.4 million, against
its $57 million production budget.
Nicolas Cage stated that he was "done" with the Ghost Rider
films and a planned sequel was cancelled.
The film rights to the character reverted to Marvel Studios shortly thereafter, and the
Robbie Reyes version of Ghost Rider appeared in Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D.
The film explores themes of dying and death, skeleton, angel, monk, superhero.
The tone is dark and intense.